[Music]
foreign
Level Training
so this is our lesson 6 in terms of
advanced level training
but it's a 21st lesson
in terms of overall present testoster
automation Concepts
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
how can we create cleanup scenarios and
then how can we use cleanup scenarios by
using present testoster latest version
60. please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so now let us understand what is
this cleanup scenario and why do we need
to use this cleanup scenario in Tasker
so by end of this lesson you will be
able to create and use cleanup scenario
and this is very useful when recovery
scenario is unrecovered so whenever your
recovery scenario is unrecovered then
these cleanup scenarios comes into
picture
so if recovery scenario fails if you
want Tasker to reset and restart your
application or your system under test
and put it into the correct status of
for your next test case right then you
can use these cleanup scenarios
and whenever test case is not
recoverable cleanup scenario will
start
clean up a testing environment so that
it will be ready or it is ready for your
next test case run
okay and cleanup scenarios can be added
to recovery scenarios connection so
basically the recovery scenarios as well
as as well as the cleanup scenarios both
will be added to recovery scenario
collections
so now let's jump onto the system and
see how can we create and use cleanup
scenarios by using latest version try
sentence task as 60.
okay so this is uh my task of 16 okay so
let us first understand
the scenario where you would need a
cleaner scenario to be created okay for
that I just created one test case okay
it's a very simple end-to-end test case
where we'll be navigating to the webshop
and then you're gonna log in and then
you are gonna purchase the blue jeans
you're going to add to cart and then
you're gonna complete your checkout
process okay so you're going to purchase
the blue jeans okay so that's what the
scenario okay let me just run this
particular test case so I already
explained automating this end-to-end
test case in my previous sessions okay
so I would recommend you guys to visit
my previous sessions so let me just run
this test case okay
so it opens your webshop
Okay click done login and then enter the
username password
right and then it's going to purchase
the blue jeans
add to cart
and then agree the terms of services
right so you remember agreeing the terms
of services where you will be checking
the Box okay
so
so this is our straight forward scenario
purchasing a blue jeans successfully
order has been placed and close the
browser log out and close the browser so
now
what if
this test case gets failed in Middle
where let's say verifying the prices for
example while
start checkout process right here while
checking out the process let's assume
the terms of service okay let's say I'm
gonna fail this test case okay at terms
of service it's not going to click on uh
the terms and uh it's we are not going
to accept the terms and conditions then
what happens it's going to throw an
error message saying that you have not
accepted the terms and conditions so in
this case this test case will fail
okay let's save this so when this test
case fails
we need to trigger cleanup scenario
so that your environment will be cleaned
up and it is ready for your next test
case so when you actually let's go back
to webshop again okay
so what happens when you do that okay
let's say login
I'm logging into my
okay logged in okay so now once I log in
let's say apparents and choose so what
I'm doing actually I am clicking on this
I'm adding quantity of 10 to the cart
correct
and then going to shopping cart here
instead of agreeing this I just clicked
on checkout then you're gonna get this
error message so then what happens your
your test case will fail
so once your test case fails
your website should be ready for your
next test case execution
so when I log in again what happens
right in your shopping cart this blue
jeans will be added it's already added
so what you need to do to recover or to
put your environment to the same state
first you need to empty this shopping
cart and log out and close the browser
why I need to log out because whenever
you enter one more time next time right
you've directly Landing onto your
website with login see I can see I
already logged in and in the shopping
cart I can see 10
items already there right so when you
when your next test case is triggered
by default your website will be landed
in such a way that you are already
logged in and you have some items in the
shopping cart
so that's why it's very necessary for
you to
empty the shopping cart and log out
right that's what you need to do
execute your next test case right so
that's why hey what I'm gonna do I'm
gonna create one
recovery scenario where at here right
click sorry recovery scenario collection
right click and then
create your recur recovery scenario
collection okay
so what I'm gonna do
so right click here
and then create a recovery scenario
add recovery scenario collection okay so
let me just again show you okay at the
test case and top of the test case I'm
actually adding a recovery scenario
collection
under this I'm gonna add a clean up
scenario create cleanup scenario
okay
so here
under this create cleanup scenario I'm
gonna drag see this is my empty shopping
contest case Okay drag and drop your
empty shopping cart test case
okay
right
so I just created one cleanup scenario
where it's gonna navigate to the
shopping cart it's gonna if you remember
emptying shopping cart by using while
loop right I already told you in my
previous session where I have explained
you how to use while loop so this is
what the example I showed you how can we
empty the shopping cart by using wine
okay the same test case I just dragged
and dropped into my cleanup scenario now
to fail this previous test case I
already removed this deleting my terms
and service
because I don't want to check
I don't want to agree the terms and
services right so that's why I'm
deleting that value so now if you see
here the structure
I have a recovery scenario at
the parent level now I have one test
case related to clean up scenario right
so when I execute this cleanup scenario
to execute this scene up cleanup
scenario one more thing is your recovery
scenarios can be triggered only
when you execute your test Case by using
execution list
so now let me
drag and drop my
recovery scenario your test case okay
so let me simply
execute this test Case by using
the recovery scenario okay so this is my
cleanup scenario test case okay
okay let me just delete clean up
everything okay
so now let me execute this cleanup
scenario when I execute this cleanup
scenario my test case is going to fail
and then it should trigger my recovery
scenario okay so now let's right click
and run this
exhibition
so now it's going to log in right
and then apparelence and choose
and it is going to add the genes and
here once you go to shopping cart see
now I'm not checking in that let's go
check out see you're giving me a error
now the test case will fail
but
recovery scenario will trigger
which
will
empty the shopping see it emptied the
shopping cart it's logged out and then
close the browser so if you see here
your test case is failed but the
recovery scenario got triggered see here
you see here
sorry
I think this one okay yeah this one see
here
here you are not able to
complete your checkout process correct
because of the
agreement
and here this test case is failed now
cleanup scenario got triggered and which
cleaned up your environment by
navigating to shopping cart
empty the shopping cart logged out and
then close the browser now you are ready
to execute your next test case
so hope you all understand how to use
your recovery scenariosis really really
very important how can you use your
cleanup scenario and what is the purpose
of your cleanup scenario and how can you
trigger the cleanup scenario okay so if
you have any queries leave your comments
in the comment box I'll try to respond
to your queries thank you
thank you